Satya Bhaskar

Director - Delivery | Recruitment Head | Operations – Process Expert | Customer Success Specialist |
Scrum Master | Trust & Safety Professional | Story Teller - Script Writer - Creative Director |
Pet Parent & Animal Lover |

Location: Hyderabad, India

Email: satya.bhaskar@gmail.com

Phone: +91 97041 60987

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/satyaarja/

Summary of Qualifications:

Professional and resourceful **Business / HR Specialist with over 17 years experience** in the strategic and tactical areas within IT Resource Management, Sourcing, Recruitment, talent acquisition, Business development, Organizational effectiveness and executive coaching both IT and Non-IT.

Education:

- Masters Degree in Human Resource & Business Administration, 2005 IBMT Business School, Bangalore, India
- Bachelor's Degree in Hospitality Management, 2002
 M.S. Ramaiah Institute of Technology, Bangalore, India

Certifications:

- Certified Scrum Master, CSM, Scrum Alliance
- Domain Certifications

Recruitment

- Certified Global Recruitment Analyst
- Certified Recruitment Manager
- > Certified Talent Acquisition Specialist

HRM

- > Certified Human Resource Generalist
- > Certified Strategic Human Capital Management
- SAP SuccessFactors Certifications [In process]
- > Recruiting Management
- Onboarding
- > Employee Central

Professional Experience:

Director - Delivery MSGen Inc. Subsidiary of Technogen Inc. Location: Hyderabad, India

Period: Feb 2022 - Present

Roles and responsibilities

 Head of entire operational aspects of MSGen and focus on Building Client Relationship and managing their needs, Building my team and their Capabilities, Building the organization Portfolio amongst other responsibilities.

Who we are:

• MS Gen Technologies is a Leader in Microsoft Technology Workforce & Software solutions.

Services:

- Product Development
- Cloud Services
- Data Technology (BI)
- Software Services
- Professional Services
- Strategic Staffing
- Managed Services

BOP Consultants Pvt. Ltd

Subsidiary of Beacon Systems Inc. (BeaconGov), Florida, USA

Location: Bangalore, India

Period: Dec 2007 – Jan 2022 [Multiple Roles]

Recruitment Head Jan 2016 – Jan 2022

Recruiting Team Lead Sep 2013 – Dec 2015

Principal Technical Recruiter Jan 2012 - Aug 2013

Senior Technical Recruiter July 2008 - Dec 2011

Technical Recruiter Dec 2007 – June 2008

Roles and responsibilities

- Servicing major accounts including direct accounts as well as MSP accounts while reviving and expanding relationships with each.
- Managing the entire staffing process; from manager debriefing to putting together job descriptions, to checking references and negotiating offers with candidates.
- Building and maintaining rapport and relationships with Hiring Managers, Project Managers, Vendor Program Coordinators and IT procurement Managers to obtain and expand business from them.
- Providing direction, strategic and tactical leadership while meeting the delivery target competency aligned.
- Client engagement, consultative, partnering from request to delivery.
- Handling the recruitment cycle for direct US Govt Clients.
- Assimilate business demand; implementing and executing staffing strategies to provide a qualified candidate pool.
- Manage hiring manager's and candidate's expectations throughout the hiring process cycle.
- Partner closely with hiring manager, senior manager and staffing consultant. Manage vendor efficiency and delivery.
- Fostered a team environment in the group and demonstrated collaborative leadership.
- Developing, implementing and monitoring effective recruitment methodologies and strategies

- Responsible for the day-to-day activities of the Recruitment Team, ensure the team meets the HR Recruitment SLAs (Service Level Agreements)
- Mentoring, providing strategy, continuously identifying & servicing business opportunities and formulating business plans.
- To prioritize and close positions in a short time.
- Maintain good conversion ratios focusing on quality
- To understand clients requirements from Client Hiring managers, line Managers stressing for Must have skills, soft skills and secondary skills
- Strategizing and executing large recruitment programs
- Ensure an optimum recruitment cycle and ratios
- Deep understanding on SRLC (Software Recruitment Life Cycle)
- Clear understanding of the dynamics of IT recruitment
- Effective team management, planning and execution skills
- Building team spirit to reach high end results through brainstorming
- Established relationships with all the clients to support high volume opportunities.
- Interact with the clients to understand the requirements and find a suitable candidate for same within a given time frame.
- Take care of our client's manpower requirements, including contractual staff and staffing. Manage and monitor sourcing strategy and manage recruitment costs & efficiency.
- Responsible for 'End to End' service delivery Process management for Talent acquisition [recruiting, staffing] for our Employment Process Outsourcing projects.
- The tasks include drafting and mapping process plans, process kick offs, scope validation, quality definition, Piloting, base lining, resource planning & final Ramp-up.
- Achieve operational efficiency within the agreed targets with multiple projects.
- Manage Client Relations to continuously focus on the enhancement of operational performance and service delivery.
- Led Quality management initiatives like ISO 9001-2000 and process re-engineering for continual process improvement.
- Team management initiatives like coaching, counseling, training and motivation.
- Specializing in information technology, research, and program management.
- Skilled at managing proposal operations and lifecycle, business development/capture, and all aspects of
 technical proposal writing and business writing processes. Main areas of expertise include: IT services
 from enterprise architecture to data centers, cloud services, network engineering and mobile
 applications, penetration testing, help desk operations, and software development/deployment for DoD
 and federal clientele. Experienced in Program Management, Administrative and Technical Services,
 Military and Engineering, and General Technical Staffing and Support.
- Assisted in analyzing Requests for Proposal (RFP)/Bid Requirements against Proposal Outlines to
 ensure both compliance and responsiveness to the customer's issues and needs
- Wrote many responses to Requests for Information [RFI], Requests for Proposals (RFPs) and Sources Sought Notices by using relevant Past Performance abstracts, sometimes under tight deadlines.
- Updated Past Performance summaries to include current data on Contract Values, Points of Contacts, and Periods of Performance.
- Updated a One-Page Marketing Statement that included the company' capabilities and relevant contracts.
- Performed Final Edits/Proofreading of proposals prior to submission.
- Researches and monitors business opportunities, and applies knowledge of service offerings and staff capabilities in respond to requests.
- Creates templates and shells for RFI, RFP, and RFQ responses
- Reviews and edits proposal inputs from teammates
- Edits and formats proposal documentation based on RFP requirements
- Writes, edits, and tailors resumes to customer specific required and desired skills for multiple positions.
- Works closely with candidates, internal personnel, and recruiters to create clear and specific rationales.

- Interfaces with candidates via email and phone call to provide best possible responses to requirements, through direct input and guidance
- Designs and produces packaging and materials for proposal submittal
- Supports business development activities, including the development of labor rates.
- Writes, proofreads, and edits responses to Requests for Proposals (RFPs) and data calls.
- Identifies and interviews candidates, and staffs positions.
- Attends business develop meetings with partners, customers, and Government personnel.
- Tracks deliverables and ensures that deadlines are met.
- Recognized for independence and creative thinking in business capture and development, leading to new areas of business and corporate growth.
- Advanced knowledge of Deltek, Gov-Win, and Fed Biz Ops databases in business development and research on new opportunities.
- Works closely with senior Subject Matter Experts (SME's), senior engineers, and executive management in defining proposal solutions and technical write-ups.
- Clients included Navy Seaport-E, U.S. Army/U.S. Air Force, DOI, DOS, DHS, FEMA and other military commands and government agencies.

Syntel Inc.

Location: Pune, India Client: Allstate

Designations: Asst. PMO / Support Consultant for SAP HR

Period: Feb 2006 - Dec 2007

Asst.PMO

Roles and responsibilities

- Project Infrastructure Management Coordinates operational procedures and project environments, including obtaining workspace, creating document standards and procedures and providing office support.
- **Project Organization and Staffing** Responsible for deriving an overall resource plan from the individual project plans, and for coordinating and managing these resources.
- Master Work Plan and Schedule Responsible for deriving an account level work plan and schedule from the individual project plans, and for tracking and reporting of ongoing performance.
- **Risk Management** Risk is assessed at the project team level and managed at the PMO to include identifying potential risks, assessing total account exposure and monitoring plans.
- Cost/Schedule Performance Management Ensures that no work is undertaken until planned and approved by implementing project tracking and status reporting processes. Also monitors team progress to plan, and summarizes and communicates accomplishments.
- Data and Documents Management Responsible for managing all project data by establishing, maintaining and disposing of project records and recording, tracking and communicating status of deliverables and collecting and maintaining processes, metrics and lessons learned.
- Communications Management Develops and implements a coordinated communication plan, with the assistance of each project. This includes identifying, tracking and resolving issues and action items, summarizing and reporting on project deliverables, and addressing the communications needs of all stakeholders.
- **Quality Management** QM processes are established utilizing specialized Quality Management resources. Individual project reviews are conducted.

SAP HR Analyst Programmer Roles and responsibilities

- Handling of Trouble Tickets in Personnel Administration (PA) & Organizational Management (OM)
- Helping customer in solving problem by providing production support.

Vee Technologies

Location: Bangalore, India
Designation: HR Generalist [Intern]
Period: June 2004 - Jan 2005

Roles and responsibilities

- Recruitments, Payroll & compensation-management
- Performance Management, Competency-Mapping, Employee welfare activities
- Exit formalities, full & final settlement